Guide to the Paul LeBlanc Papers, 1967-1998 AIS.1974.17
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Paul J. LeBlanc Papers
1967-1998
ULS Archives & Special Collections
LeBlanc, Paul J.
AIS.1974.17
43.75 Linear Feet (35 Boxes)
The Paul J. LeBlanc Papers consists of mainly left-leaning, typically socialist, material collected by LeBlanc in his professional and personal life. The collection includes magazines, newspapers and articles. There is also information about various socialist groups, especially the Fourth International Tendency, of which LeBlanc is a member. Additionally, the collection contains both professional and personal correspondence, research materials used by LeBlanc and articles he has written.
Related Material
James Dolsen Political Left Pamphlets Collection, 1918-1996, AIS.1999.11, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Robert Opie Shepherd Papers Relating to the Democratic Socialists of America, AIS.1990.21, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
A.E. Forbes Communist Collection, 1921-1972, AIS.2000.07, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Lawrence F. Evans Collection, 1978-1988, AIS.1988.17, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Political and Social Activist Movements Collection, 1968-1975, AIS.1974.17, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
New American Movement, Pittsburgh Chapter Records, 1973-1982, AIS.1989.18, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Thomas Merton Center Records, 1971-2004, AIS.1982.19, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following five series:
Series I. Publications
Series II. Fourth Internationalist Tendency
Series III. Organizations
Series IV. Research
Series V. Personal
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Paul J. LeBlanc Papers, 1968-1998, AIS.1974.17, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Biography
Paul LeBlanc is an academic and activist interested in socialism, various aspects of Marxism and workers rights. He graduated from the University of Pittsburgh in 1971 with a degree in History and a minor in Sociology. Before continuing with his academic career, LeBlanc worked a variety of jobs, such as assembly-line worker and pipefitter. During this time he was an active member of several labor unions. In 1980 he received his Masters degree in History and in 1989 he received his Ph.D., both from the University of Pittsburgh. His studies as an undergraduate and graduate student focused on the history of labor and social movements. LeBlanc then went on to work at the University of Pittsburgh as a teaching fellow and academic advisor. He also taught courses at Carlow College and Slippery Rock University. He became a professor at LaRoche College in 2000 and remains there today.
During his academic career, his articles appeared in various publications throughout the United States and abroad. He also became involved in several organizations, most notably the Fourth Internationalist Tendency (F.I.T.), which works to promote socialism, human and workers rights and peace. F.I.T., along with the Socialist Workers Party, Socialist Action and Solidarity, worked together and exchanged information and ideas. Eventually, these organizations merged to become part of Solidarity, an umbrella organization, but still remained independent. LeBlanc was very involved in the F.I.T.'s various publications, especially The Bulletin in Defense of Marxism.
Scope Notes
The Paul LeBlanc Papers contain a variety of left-leaning, typically socialist, publications such as newspapers, magazines and newsletters. The publications are mostly domestic but foreign publications are also included. The Nation, The Guardian, Against the Current, International Socialist Review, Socialist Action and Socialist Challenge are among the most popular publications in the collection.
The collection also contains Information and Discussion Bulletins published by the F.I.T., Socialist Action, Socialists Workers Party and Solidarity. Additionally, there are many flyers, bulletins and pamphlets from other organizations – many pertaining to anti-intervention and anti-war causes. The collection also contains documents and correspondence pertaining to the F.I.T. Included are meeting minutes, proposals, resolutions and correspondence between fellow members and members of other organizations. This material shows the evolution of the F.I.T. and its relationships with Solidarity, Socialist Action and Socialist Workers Party. There is also a concentration of material that focuses on the F.I.T. publication Bulletin in Defense of Marxism.
LeBlanc's professional and academic material is also part of this collection. His research material is included, as well as a number of his articles. The collection contains drafts and the final versions of his writings. There are also many other articles and manuscripts, presumably written by colleagues and friends, that LeBlanc acquired and reviewed. LeBlanc also collected a variety of other articles and newspaper articles on topics such as politics, political theory, labor movements and free trade.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Paul LeBlanc in 1974, 1995 and 2000.
Socialism -- United States -- Newspapers; Socialism -- Periodicals; Political activists -- Pennsylvania; Social action; Personal papers; Fourth Internationalist Tendency (Group); LeBlanc, Paul J.
- Publications, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series consists of newspapers, magazines, bulletins and books collected by LeBlanc. The majority of the publications reflect LeBlanc's activism in various left-leaning social and political groups. Also included are publications put out by organizations that LeBlanc or the F.I.T. were associated with, such as Solidarity and the Socialist Workers Party. This series contains well known publications such as The Nation and The Guardian, as well as smaller, more localized publications.
  - 1917: Journal of the International Bolshevik Revolution (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 99P/SEIU Organizer, the Voice of Health Care Workers in Pennsylvania (Box 1, Item 1)
  - The Abolitionist (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACLU Pittsburgh Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Across Frontiers (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Action (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Activists Panels (Box 1, Item 3)
  - African American Nation: A Journal for Self-Determination and Workers Power (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Against the Current (Box 1, Item 4-92)
  - Agreement on Ending the War and Restoring Peace in Vietnam (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alert! (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Allegheny Socialist (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alliance for the Progressive Action (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Ally (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alternative Press Index (Box 2, Item 1-2)
  - The Alternative Review (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - America at Work (Box 2, Item 3)
  - America Needs a Raise Newsletter (Box 2, Item 4)
  - America Needs a Raise: Facts and Figures (Box 2, Item 5-6)
  - American Elections and the Issues Facing Working People (Box 2, Item 7-8)
  - American Labor (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The American Socialist (Box 2, Item 9)
  - The American Spectator (Box 2, Item 10)
  - American Student (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - AMM for Activists (Box 2, Item 11)
  - Amnesty Action (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Another Voice, Another Vision: Labor Parties in American History (Box 2, Item 12)
  - Anti-Racist Action News (Box 2, Item 13-15)
  - Autre Chose (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Avortement: la femme decide (Box 2, Item 16)
  - Bandera Socialista (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Baragua! (Box 2, Item 17)
  - Barricada Internacional (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Battleground Detroit (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - BCR Reports (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Bill of Rights Journal (Box 2, Item 18-19)
  - The Birth and Development of the Black Student Movement, 1960-1990 (Box 2, Item 20)
  - Black History and the Class Struggle (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bolerium Books (Box 2, Item 21-26)
  - Bookmarks (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Books for an Endangered Planet from Charles H. Kerr (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Brazil (Box 2, Item 27)
  - The Brecht Forum (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bring the Troops Home Now Newsletter (Box 2, Item 28-49)
  - Building a Movement for Reproductive Freedom (Box 2, Item 50)
  - The Bulletin (Box 2, Item 51)
  - Bulletin for International Conference Stop Capitalist Barbarism Prepare the Socialist Alternative (Box 2, Item 52)
  - Bulletin of International Socialism (Box 2, Item 53)
  - Cahiers du Feminisme (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Call (Box 2, Item 54)
  - Campaign for a New Tomorrow Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Campaign Group News (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Capitalism, Nature, Socialism: A Journal of Socialist Ecology (Box 2, Item 55-56)
  - Capitalism, the Family and Personal Life (Box 2, Item 57)
  - CAQ: Covert Action (Box 2, Item 58)
  - The Catholic Worker (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Celebrate Diversity (Box 2, Item 59)
  - Central America Mobilization Coalition Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Central North Side Newsletter (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Challenge: the Revolutionary Communist Newspaper (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Charles H. Kerr - Publishers of Anti-Establishment Literature (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cheetay (Box 2, Item 60)
  - China Reconstructs (Box 2, Item 61)
  - The Christian Century (Box 2, Item 62)
  - Citizen Action News (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Columbia Journalism Review (Box 2, Item 63)
  - Columbia Update (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Commentary (Box 2, Item 64)
  - Committee of Youth Organizations Information Bulletin (Box 2, Item 65)
  - Committees of Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Concessions and How to Beat Them (a Labor Notes Book) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Conch (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Conference on Strengthening the New Politics (Box 2, Item 66)
  - Conspiracy (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Corresponder (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Counter-Attack (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Crisis (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Crisis in Chicago: 1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - A Critical History of New Politics in Berkley by Peter Camejo (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - The Critical Point (Box 2, Item 67)
  - Critique Communiste (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Cross Roads (Box 2, Item 68-78)
  - Cuba Speaks out on the Helms-Burton Law (Box 2, Item 79)
  - Cuban Labor and the Communist Party, 1937-1958 (Box 2, Item 80)
  - Cultural Correspondence (Box 2, Item 81-82)
  - The Current Economic Crisis: Causes and Implications (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Current History (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Daily World (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Democratic Credo: Economic Bill of Rights (Box 3, Item 2)
  - Democratic Left (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Detroit Sunday Journal (Box 3, Item 3)
  - Dialogue and Initiative (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Dispatcher (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dissent (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dissent (Box 3, Item 4)
  - Dollars and Sense (Box 3, Item 5-13)
  - Ecology and Development (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Education for Socialists (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Eleven-Ninety-Nine Drug and Hospital News (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Em Tempo (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Envio (Box 3, Item 14)
  - The Ethiopian Revolution (Box 3, Item 15)
  - Extra! (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fascism and the Spectacular State (Box 3, Item 16)
  - Falling Short (Box 3, Item 17)
  - Federation for Industrial Retention and Renewal News (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Feminists and Anti-Feminists in the French Revolution (Box 3, Item 18)
  - Fifty Contemporary American Artists (Box 3, Item 19)
  - A Fight for Political Rights (Box 3, Item 20)
  - Fighting for Women's Rights in the 1990's (Box 3, Item 21)
  - Fighting Worker (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Filmmakers Library (Box 3, Item 22)
  - For the Sake of a Single Verse (Box 3, Item 23)
  - Forward Motion (Box 3, Item 24)
  - Fourth International (Box 3, Item 25)
  - The Fourth International: The Long March of the Trotskyists (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Free Speech and Free Press (Box 3, Item 26)
  - Free Speech Movement Newsletter (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Free Student (Box 3, Item 27)
  - Free University Press (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Freedom Socialist (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Freedom Now (Box 3, Item 28)
  - Frente Unido Newsletter (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Friends of Yesh Gvul (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - From Nuremburg to Harrisburg (Box 3, Item 29)
  - Fuera de Linea (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Global Exchanges (Box 3, Item 30)
  - Going for it: How to Run a Grassroots Election Campaign and Win (Box 3, Item 31)
  - Golden Jubilee of de Leonism: 1890-1940 (Box 3, Item 32)
  - Grass Roots (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - The Graven Image (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Green Left Weekly (Box 3, Folder 24-29)
  - The Guardian (Box 3, Folder 30-37)
  - Hammer or Anvil: The Story of the German Working-Class Movement (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Haymarket (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Health Right News (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Heart Quarterly (Box 4, Item 2)
  - Hell on Wheels (Box 4, Item 3)
  - The History Review Journal (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - How to Beat the Racists (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Humanities Press (Box 4, Item 4-19)
  - I.F. Stone's Weekly (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Il Programma Comunista (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
  - I'll Be There - Jobs With Justice Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - I'm All Right (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Illustrated News (Box 4, Item 20)
  - In Defense of the Revolutionary Continuity (Box 4, Item 21)
  - In Pittsburgh Newsweekly (Box 4, Folder 13-15)
  - In These Times (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Independent Political Action Bulletin (Box 4, Item 22-23)
  - Independent Politics (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Independent Progressive Politics Network (Box 4, Item 24)
  - The Indonesian Massacre (Box 4, Item 25)
  - Industrial Worker (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Infusion (Box 4, Item 26)
  - Inpre Cor (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Inroads: Harvard's Socialist Forum (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Institute of Social Studies - Working Paper Series (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Instructor's Manual for Taking Sides (Box 4, Item 27)
  - Insurgent (Box 4, Item 28-29)
  - Interlink (Box 4, Item 30)
  - International Discussion Bulletin (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
  - International Discussion Bulletin for the XIII World Congress (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - International Institute for Research and Education (Box 4, Item 31)
  - International Internal Discussion Bulletin (Box 4, Folder 27-35)
  - International Marxist Review (Box 4, Item 32)
  - International Newsletter of Historical Studies on Comintern/Communism/Stalinism (Box 4, Item 33)
  - International Outlook (Box 4, Item 34)
  - International Revolution (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - International Socialist Review (Box 5, Folder 1-22)
  - International Solidarity (Box 5, Item 1)
  - International Trotskyist (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - International Viewpoint (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Internationaler (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Internationalist Papers 3 & 4 (Box 5, Item 2-3)
  - The Irish Rebel (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Is the 'Rainbow' a Real Alternative? A Socialist Response (Box 5, Item 4)
  - Issues and Studies (Box 5, Item 5)
  - The Jamal Journal (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Jewish Currents (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
  - Jewish Liberation Journal (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Jongerenkrant Rebel (Box 5, Item 6)
  - Justice (Box 5, Item 7)
  - Justice Speaks (Box 5, Folder 31-32)
  - La Gauche (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - la tragedie du viet nam: chronique ordinaire 1920-1945 (Box 5, Item 8)
  - La Verite (Box 5, Item 9-10)
  - Labor Militant (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Labor Notes (Box 5, Folder 35-39)
  - Labor Outreach (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Labor Party Advocate (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Labor Party Press (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Labor Review (Box 6, Item 1-2)
  - Labor Solidarity (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Labor's Heritage (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Labour Focus on Eastern Europe (Box 6, Item 3)
  - Labour Review (Box 6, Item 4-19)
  - Labour's Independent Weekly Tribune (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - La Manifeste Communiste: 150 ans apres (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - La Marxisme aujourd'hui (Box 6, Item 20)
  - Left Bank Distribution Book Catalog (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Left Green Notes - A Magazine of Radical Ecology (Box 6, Item 21)
  - Left Green Notes Organizing Bulletin of the Left Green Network (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Left History "From Marxism to Conservatism" (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Left Out Newsletter (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Left Report (Box 6, Item 22)
  - Left Review (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Left Turn (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Lenin and the Theory of 'Democratic Dictatorship' (Box 6, Item 23)
  - The Leninist Theory of Organization (Box 6, Item 24)
  - Leon Trotsky and the Organizational Principles of the Revolutionary Party (Box 6, Item 25)
  - Lessons of the P-9 Strike (Box 6, Item 26)
  - Liberation (Box 6, Item 27-29)
  - Liberation! (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Liberator (Box 6, Item 30-31)
  - Libertad! (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - LINKS (Box 6, Item 32-33)
  - Links: International Journal of Socialist Renewal (Box 6, Item 34-38)
  - The Listener from WYEP (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - London Labour Briefing (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - MacNeil and Lehrer News Hour Conversation with Castro (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The Magazine (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Malcolm X: Fighter for Black Liberation (Box 6, Item 39)
  - Man and the Arts: A Marxist Approach (Box 6, Item 40)
  - Maoism in the US: A Critical History of the Progressive Labor Party (Box 6, Item 41)
  - Marxism Today (Box 6, Item 42)
  - Marxisme et Parti (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Marxism's Lessons for Today by Ann Robertson (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Marxist Education Bulletin (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Mayday (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - The Meaning of Gorbachev's Reforms (Box 6, Item 43)
  - Metro Pittsburgh Labor Party Newsletter (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - The Michigan Militant (Box 6, Item 44)
  - Michigan Quarterly Review (Box 6, Item 45)
  - Middle East Research and Information Project (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
  - The Militant (Box 6, Folder 28-40)
  - Militant - The Marxist Paper for Labour and Youth (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - The Mill Hunk Herald (Box 7, Item 1)
  - Miners Voice (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Modern Times (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Monthly Review (Box 7, Item 2-5)
  - Monthly Review Press (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
  - Monthly Review Sustainers' Newsletter (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - The Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee Reporter (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Moving On (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - NACLA - Report on the Americas (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Nation (Box 7, Folder 9-23)
  - New American Movement Discussion Bulletin (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - The New Emancipation (Box 7, Item 6)
  - New Left Notes (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - The New Republic (Box 7, Item 7-8)
  - New Party News (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - The New People (Box 7, Folder 27-28)
  - The New People (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
  - The New Socialist (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - New Solidarity (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - New Statesmen (Box 8, Item 1)
  - The New Teamsters (Box 8, Item 2)
  - New Unionist (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The New York Marxist School (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - New York Newsday (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The New York Review of Books (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - New York Times (Box 8, Item 3)
  - The New York Times Magazine (Box 8, Item 4)
  - News and Letters (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - News from the War Zone (Box 8, Item 5)
  - News from Within (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - The Newsletter (Box 8, Item 6)
  - Newsletter of International Labour Studies (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - North Star (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Northland Poster Collective (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Notebooks for Study and Research (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Octobre 17 Colloque (Box 8, Item 7)
  - October Review - China, Marxism and Democracy (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Of the People, for the People: Pictorial Highlights of the Fifty Years of the CP USA (Box 8, Item 8)
  - On Guard (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - On the Line (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Open City: Voice of the City-Wide Strike (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Organize! 6th Labor Notes Conference (Box 8, Item 9)
  - Organized Labor - New Times, New Problems, New Ideas (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - The Organizer (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
  - Organizing the YSA (Box 8, Folder 27-28)
  - The Origins of Left Culture in the U.S.: 1880-1940 (Box 8, Item 10)
  - Osaale News (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Our Crisis Economy: The End of the Boom (Box 8, Item 11)
  - Outcry! From Occupied Berkley (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - The Partisan (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Peace and Democracy (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Peace and Freedom News (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - The Peace Educator (Box 8, Item 12)
  - Peacemaking Journal - The National Conference on Peacemaking and Conflict Resolution (Box 8, Item 13)
  - Peninsula Letters (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Journal (Box 8, Item 14)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Notes (Box 8, Item 15)
  - Pennsylvania Peace Links (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - The People (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - People's Daily World (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - People's Song (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - People's Tribune (Box 8, Item 16)
  - People's Weekly World (Box 8, Folder 39-41)
  - Perspectives - American Historical Association Newsletter (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - The Philadelphia Inquirer (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Philadelphia Marxist School (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - The Pitt News (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Pittsburgh History (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - The Plane Truth (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Planet (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Plans for Destruction of Collective Bargaining in 1963 (Box 8, Item 17)
  - PLANTA Newsletter (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - The Plough Box (Box 9, Item 1-2)
  - Policing by Consent (Box 9, Item 3)
  - Political Affairs: Journal of Marxist Thought (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Postmark Praha (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Poverty in the American Dream: Women and Children First (Box 9, Item 4)
  - Precept and Example (Box 9, Item 5)
  - The Premature Obituary of Socialism (Box 9, Item 6)
  - Progress Books Information Bulletin (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Progressive (Box 9, Item 7-8)
  - Progressive Labor (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Progressive Women's Quarterly (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Proletarian Revolution (Box 9, Item 9)
  - Propaganda Review (Box 9, Item 10)
  - Proud Heritage: A Brief History of the United Steelworkers of America (Box 9, Item 11)
  - Radical America (Box 9, Item 12)
  - Radical America Newsletter (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Radical Philosophy Review of Books (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Radical Therapist (Box 9, Item 13)
  - Religious Socialism (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Rethinking Marxism (Box 9, Item 14)
  - The Return of the Social Revolution: Movements of the 60s in Historical Perspective (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - The Review of Radical Political Economics (Box 9, Folder 10-12)
  - Reviews in American History: On Native Grounds (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Revolutionary Marxism Today (Box 9, Item 15-16)
  - Revolutionary Marxist Papers 8 (Box 9, Item 17)
  - Revolutionary Worker (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Revolutionary Youth Movement (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Rising Up Angry (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - The Rocket (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Root and Branch (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Rotten Propaganda (Box 9, Item 18)
  - Rumbo Latino (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Russian Labour Review (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - San Francisco Review (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Sanity (Box 9, Item 19)
  - Saturday Review of the Sciences (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Savvy Troublemaking: Politics for New Labor Activists (Box 9, Item 20)
  - Scholar (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Scholar Warrior Journal (Box 9, Item 21)
  - Science and Society (Box 9, Item 22)
  - Science as Culture (Box 9, Item 23-24)
  - SDS: 101 From the Inside (Box 9, Item 25)
  - Self Management as a Key to the Economy of the XXI Century (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Shakedown (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Sierra (Box 9, Item 26)
  - The Smithsonian (Box 9, Item 27)
  - Social Education (Box 9, Item 28)
  - Socialism or Barbarism (Box 9, Item 29)
  - Socialism Today (Box 9, Item 30)
  - The Socialist (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Socialist Action (Box 9, Folder 27-33)
  - Socialist Action Internal Discussion Bulletin (Box 9, Folder 34-37)
  - Socialist Action Internal Discussion Bulletin (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Socialist Action Internal Information Bulletin (Box 10, Folder 3)